<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Apache Arrow DataFusion Comet Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section id="Codebase+IP+Clearance+TEMPLATE">
            <title>Codebase IP Clearance for Apache Arrow DataFusion Comet</title>
        </section>
        <section id="XYZ+Codebase+Intellectual+Property+%28IP%29+Clearance+Status">
            <title>Apache Arrow DataFusion Comet Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
        </section>
        <section id="Description">
            <title>Description</title>
            <p>Apache Arrow DataFusion Comet is a Spark native engine powered by Apache Arrow DataFusion and the Rust
                implementation of Apache Arrow. It is being donated as a new repository within the Apache Arrow project
                and consists of approximately 6,000 lines of code.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Project+info">
            <title>Project info</title>
            <ul>
                <li>The Apache Arrow PMC will be responsible for the code</li>
            </ul>
            <ul>
                <li>It will be integrated into the Apache Arrow project in a new repository</li>
            </ul>
            <ul>
                <li>Officer or member managing donation: Andy Grove (Apache Arrow PMC Member)</li>
            </ul>
            <p>
                <em>Completed tasks are shown by the completion date (YYYY-MM-dd).</em>
            </p>
            <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
                <title>Identify the codebase</title>
                <table>
                    <tr>
                        <th>date</th>
                        <th>item</th>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>2024-02-03</td>
                        <td>A United States Trademark Search shows that there are a number of wordmark trademarks for
                            COMET in computer software, but none conflict with the scope of the Apache Arrow DataFusion
                            Comet project.

                            There are a few that mention data analytics, but in the context of analyzing specific types
                            of data (e.g. education data and website analytics) as part of a hosted service, and none of
                            them are related to building a Spark native engine.

                            <b>COMET INFORMATICS LLC (LIMITED LIABILITY COMPANY; NEW YORK, USA)</b>

                            Class 042
                            100 101.
                            G &amp; S: IC 042: Providing on-line, non-downloadable, web-based computer software applications
                            and an on-line interactive database for temporary use for use by educational institutions
                            and not-for-profit organizations for the collection, centralized storage, analysis, and
                            reporting of qualitative and quantitative data or information related to children or
                            students, teachers or child professionals, principals or program directors, schools or
                            programs, and/or school districts or communities.

                            <b>Comet ML, Inc. (CORPORATION; DELAWARE, USA)</b>

                            Class 042
                            100 101.
                            G &amp; S: IC 042: Computer services, namely, hosting and maintaining an on-line web site and
                            platform for others for collaboratively brainstorming, developing, managing, planning,
                            coordinating, modifying, tracking, testing, reviewing, publishing and archiving digital
                            computer programs including machine learning and artificial intelligence, documentation,
                            technical, documents, contracts, sprints, stories, bugs and issues; consulting services in
                            the field of artificial intelligence; consulting services in the field of design, selection,
                            implementation and use of computer hardware and software systems for others; IT consulting
                            services.

                            <b>University Corporation for AtmosphericResearch (CORPORATION; COLORADO, USA)</b>

                            Class 009
                            026 038.
                            G &amp; S: IC 009: computer software, printed documentation, audio tapes, video tapes and
                            compact discs all containing meteorological training and educational information all sold as
                            a unit.

                            <b>Advanced Medical Predictive Devices, Diagnostics and Displays, Inc. (CORPORATION; VIRGINIA,
                            USA)</b>

                            Class 042
                            100 101.
                            G &amp; S: IC 042: Software as a service (SAAS) services featuring software for assessing risk
                            of certain sub-acute medical conditions.

                            <b>Cox Enterprises, Inc. (CORPORATION; DELAWARE, USA)</b>

                            Class 042
                            100 101.
                            G &amp; S: IC 042: Software as a service (SAAS) services, namely, providing online
                            non-downloadable computer software for data collection, data analytics, and audience
                            measurement and insight, and compiling demographic, lifestyle, and/or behavioral data of
                            existing and potential consumers, and segmentation and distribution of such data; and
                            providing non-downloadable software platforms, algorithms and interfaces for social media
                            and website monitoring, data mining, news monitoring, customer relations monitoring,
                            consumer/customer sentiment monitoring, brand monitoring, determination of data
                            relationships, data storage services, and extraction of content; providing online
                            non-downloadable software to perform internet marketing, website traffic optimization, and
                            business research and intelligence by utilizing data analytics, retail analytics, stream
                            processing and analytics, large volume data processing, user conversion optimization,
                            customer analysis, website visitor analysis and website analysis; providing online
                            non-downloadable software for developing, launching, displaying, editing, managing,
                            measuring, tracking and analyzing advertisements and sales and advertising campaigns.

                            <b>C/HCA, Inc. (CORPORATION; DELAWARE, USA)</b>

                            Class 009
                            021 026 038 036 023.
                            G &amp; S: IC 009: Medical care outcome reporting software for the healthcare industry.

                            <b>LAKELAND CARE, INC. (CORPORATION; MICHIGAN, USA)</b>

                            Class 042
                            100 101.
                            G &amp; S: IC 042: Providing on-line non-downloadable software for physicians to view continuing
                            education courses and to track physicians' continuing medical education credits.

                            <b>Parsons Corproration (CORPORATION; DELAWARE, USA)</b>

                            Class 009
                            026 038 021 036 023.
                            G &amp; S: IC 009: Computer software for use in energy assessment and capital planning, namely,
                            a software application for collecting and recording data about the current energy condition,
                            adequacy, inventory and usage of a building, and for calculating the Energy Utilization
                            Index, Carbon Footprint, and LEED compliance, and that is able to predict future conditions
                            through life cycling.

                            <b>Affinity Solutions, Inc. (CORPORATION; DELAWARE, USA)</b>

                            Class 042
                            100 101.
                            G &amp; S: IC 042: Providing online non-downloadable software for enabling users to review,
                            analyze, report and export processed data from a secure, curated database of
                            consumer-permissioned purchase data and to combine, compare and match such data with data
                            from the user's proprietary datasets and third-party datasets, all in the field of curated
                            consumer-permissioned purchase data; providing online non-downloadable software for
                            facilitating and streamlining the creation of data solutions for strategies, insight, and
                            guidance on marketing and consumer behavior in a secure and private cloud environment, all
                            in the field of curated consumer-permissioned purchase data; providing online
                            non-downloadable software featuring algorithms and step-by-step processes for enabling users
                            to leverage purchase data, media viewing data, identity graph data and data analytic methods
                            in order to connect deterministic purchase-behavior activity to media viewing behaviors for
                            the purposes of planning, optimizing and measuring the effectiveness of media-based
                            advertising.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                </table>
                <p>
                    The code is provided in the form of a GitHub Pull Request at
                    <a href="https://github.com/apache/arrow-datafusion-comet/pull/1">https://github.com/apache/arrow-datafusion-comet/pull/1</a>.
                </p>
                <section id="Copyright">
                    <title>Copyright</title>
                    <table>
                        <tr>
                            <th>date</th>
                            <th>item</th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2024-02-03</td>
                            <td>Check and make sure that the papers that transfer rights to the ASF been received. It is
                                only necessary to transfer rights for the package, the core code, and any new code
                                produced by the project.
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2024-01-07</td>
                            <td>The changes in the <a href="https://github.com/apache/arrow-datafusion-comet/pull/1">donation PR</a>
                                include adding the ASF copyright, verified manually as well as by the automated
                                RAT check (<a href="https://github.com/apache/arrow-datafusion-comet/pull/1#issuecomment-1913367405">link</a>).
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                    </table>
                    <p>
                        Identify name recorded for software grant:
                        <em>the name of the grant as recorded
                            in the foundation/officers area, in either grants.txt or cclas.txt, so that the
                            grant can be easily identified. If recorded in the grants.txt document, use the
                            "for" or title. If recorded in the cclas.txt document, use the company name
                            (field 2 without submitter name) and the "form on file" name (field 4, without
                            any people's names).
                        </em>
                    </p>
                </section>
                <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
                    <title>Verify distribution rights</title>
                    <p>
                        Corporations and individuals holding existing distribution rights:
                    </p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>
                            <em>Apple</em>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                    <table>
                        <tr>
                            <th>date</th>
                            <th>item</th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>....-..-..</td>
                            <td>Check that all active committers have a signed CLA on
                                record.
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2024-02-03</td>
                            <td>Remind active committers that they are responsible for
                                ensuring that a Corporate CLA is recorded if such is
                                required to authorize their contributions under their
                                individual CLA (<a href="https://github.com/apache/arrow-datafusion-comet/pull/2/files#r1477120675">link</a>).
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2024-02-03</td>
                            <td>Check and make sure that for all items included with the
                                distribution that is not under the Apache license, we have
                                the right to combine with Apache-licensed code and
                                redistribute (Does not apply in this case).
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>....-..-..</td>
                            <td>Check and make sure that all items depended upon by the
                                project is covered by one or more of the following approved
                                licenses: Apache, BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or
                                something with essentially the same terms.
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                    </table>
                    <p>Generally, the result of checking off these items will be a
                        Software Grant, CLA, and Corporate CLA for ASF licensed code,
                        which must have no dependencies upon items whose licenses that
                        are incompatible with the Apache License.
                    </p>
                </section>
            </section>
            <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
                <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project
                </title>
                <p>
                    Related VOTEs:
                </p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <em>The VOTE thread accepting the donation:
                            <a href="https://lists.apache.org/thread/sk70pkhwmt8vgn0thtr04qg4mpqsgfvx">https://lists.apache.org/thread/sk70pkhwmt8vgn0thtr04qg4mpqsgfvx</a>
                        </em>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </section>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
